<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dan Tanner</title>
    <link>https://dantanner.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dan Tanner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dantanner.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin vs Java in 2021</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/kotlin-v-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/kotlin-v-java/</guid>
      <description>Since the arrival of Java 17, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard a few people wonder &amp;ldquo;Does Kotlin Still Make Sense, or Should I just use Java?&amp;rdquo;
Short answer: Kotlin is still a far better language in terms of features, and its critical advantages will probably never come to Java.
What do I consider critical advantages?
Null Safety and Immutability Kotlin lets you write elegant null-safe code, and forces you to be explicit about null-safety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>50 Million Essential Homeowner Tools</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/essential-homeowner-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/essential-homeowner-tools/</guid>
      <description>Overview This article summarizes what I think of as essential homeowner tools for people interested in basic maintenance and improvements. With the amount of information available online today, it&amp;rsquo;s easier than ever to learn. For example, I love Project Farm. Unfortunately there&amp;rsquo;s also a lot of incomplete and just plain bad information out there.
So this my attempt to condense twenty years of home ownership experience into a concise but complete starting point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaperone</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/chaperone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/chaperone/</guid>
      <description>I built a basic but extensible monitoring tool to help people watch their systems. It&amp;rsquo;s called Chaperone, and it&amp;rsquo;s open-sourced on github. It&amp;rsquo;s simple and powerful, letting you execute arbitrary scripts to determine health.
Why? A couple years ago, a bright colleague of mine whipped up a quick and elegant solution to watch and alert on a bunch of things running in our apps. We didn&amp;rsquo;t want a big overblown solution, but it also needed to be customizable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Don&#39;t Teach C to Beginning Programmers</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/please-dont-teach-c-to-beginning-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 20:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/please-dont-teach-c-to-beginning-programmers/</guid>
      <description>The Student I have a niece in her first year at a local university. She&amp;rsquo;s never done any programming before, and thinking of becoming an actuary. That means she should learn at least a little bit of programming in a tool like R or Python, right? Those seem like good high-level languages in 2019 that are also applicable in that field.
The Phone Call A few weeks ago I got a call from her Dad asking for some help with homework on an introductory (100-level) programming course titled &amp;ldquo;Problem Solving in the Natural Sciences (using C and Matlab)&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meteorologists Urged To Stop Giving 100%</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/meteorologists-urged-to-stop-giving-100-percent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 10:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/meteorologists-urged-to-stop-giving-100-percent/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished spending a year collecting and comparing forecasts from four different providers for seven different locations across the US.
Background Why Did I Do It? The petty rage of a first world problem. My phone said there was a 0% chance of rain today, but it rained. More than once. This made me curious about what the forecast data actually looked like, and how different provider predictions compare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camp Lotto</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/camp-lotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 11:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/camp-lotto/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a great family camp my family has attended over the years. We spend a week on a beautiful lake with good friends, pawn our children off for a few hours each day, and disconnect from the world.
It started as a tiny little family camp decades ago, and is now so popular there&amp;rsquo;s a lottery system held each winter to determine who gets in for the summer.
The lottery process has some major flaws though, and gives a sour taste to an otherwise well-executed operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mountain Bike Frame Hydration Hack</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/frame-hydration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 13:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/frame-hydration/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been carrying water on my frame using a custom solution the last couple seasons. I originally googled for a solution and didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything commercially available, but found lots of helpful posts in various forums explaining what folks have done. It&amp;rsquo;s worked really well, so thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a bundle of details in case anyone else is interested. If you know of an existing commercial solution that does all this, let me know and I&amp;rsquo;ll update the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown Notes</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/markdown-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 20:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/markdown-notes/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr; markdown files + file syncing + built-in OS file searching = easy organized notes
I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing more devops work the last couple years, which requires a broader and shallow level of knowledge vs. writing code in one or two languages for months at a time.
Because of the dozens of tools I need to juggle, because I forget things, and because I forget things, keeping good notes is essential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>curl saves the day</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/curl-saves-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 13:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/curl-saves-the-day/</guid>
      <description>Every developer should be comfortable with curl.
For the same reason that you should at least be conversational in tools like sed, awk, and vi, you should be able to quickly type in something like like curl -v localhost:8080 to see what&amp;rsquo;s going on. It&amp;rsquo;s available on just about every unix-based box for a good reason.
Like its man page states, the number of features will make your head spin. That&amp;rsquo;s probably the most discussed reason people are turned off by it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groovy is still better than Java</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/groovy-is-still-better-than-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 01:20:43 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/groovy-is-still-better-than-java/</guid>
      <description>The idea for this post started last week when a gifted teammate, whose experience lies outside JVM languages, asked me if it was still worth it to write Groovy over Java. Good question&amp;hellip;
For the last five years, when it comes to writing for the JVM, it&amp;rsquo;s been mostly Groovy for me.
Crap, it&amp;rsquo;s been almost ten years. dan feels his bones creaking&amp;hellip;
When I first saw Venkat Subramaniam gliding through his beautiful java to groovy idioms at a conference, I was impressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>java.time for the extremely impatient</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/javatime-for-impatient/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 02:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/javatime-for-impatient/</guid>
      <description>This is a super quick history and primer for those familiar with java, but unfamiliar with Joda-Time. Java’s original date and time handling had some issues that could make it cumbersome and error-prone to work with. Then came the Joda-Time library, which is a fantastic replacement for pretty much everything date and time related. It’s intuitive, clean, fully-featured, and performant.
Starting with Java 8, the library was folded into the core JDK, with very few modifications to the Joda API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Grails Tomcat datasource configuration with Etcd</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/dynamic-grails-tomcat-datasource/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 06:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/dynamic-grails-tomcat-datasource/</guid>
      <description>Ever wonder if you could modify a Grails datasource while the app is running? Probably not, and that&amp;rsquo;s totally fine&amp;hellip;most people don&amp;rsquo;t need to. We had a couple reasons though:
 During a disaster recovery situation where a non-clustered database goes down, you want to point all the apps at a failover database. By default this means you have to update the config and restart all the apps. On a typical AWS instance, this means at least a minute of downtime for a bigger Grails app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groovy collect vs spread-dot operator</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/groovy-collect-vs-spread-dot-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/groovy-collect-vs-spread-dot-operator/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I was doing some Groovy code cleanup with the wonderful CodeNarc static analysis tool. One of the violations it found was UnnecessaryCollectCall. The summary of the rule is &amp;ldquo;Some method calls to Object.collect(Closure) can be replaced with the spread operator.&amp;rdquo; e.g. Replace things.collect { it.name } with things*.name, or even things.name if what you&amp;rsquo;re after is a property.
But when I performed that refactoring and ran all the tests, some failed!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playhouse</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/playhouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/playhouse/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I promised Maria that I would get her and Daniela a playhouse for their birthdays. I was originally going to buy them a little Step2 playhouse, which would&amp;rsquo;ve been totally fine. But my good friend Rob, a skilled woodworker, convinced me that building a playhouse was the way to go. I was a little tentative about the idea, since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t built a real structure before on my own, but he very generously offered to help (and with two kids of his own, meant that his wife Karen also very generously helped&amp;hellip;we still can&amp;rsquo;t thank them enough!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domain names for daughters</title>
      <link>https://dantanner.com/post/domain-names-for-daughters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dantanner.com/post/domain-names-for-daughters/</guid>
      <description>Though the biggest domain name purchases are probably long-gone since the initial dot-com boom, they still remain a valued property. They&amp;rsquo;ll never be as valuable as real land of course, since we can always create more of them, as opposed to things like lake-front property.
The recent mad rush for facebook profile names reminded me of this new global scale of gold rush activity. And yes, I&amp;rsquo;m a little annoyed that someone that has been farming this interweb as long as I have was offered a name like dan.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
